in this video I need to show you an
effective method to be able to take one
vector and write it in terms of some
other basis to write it in some other
coordinate system and while I show you
the best way to do this kind of
computation I'm also going to introduce
a little bit of notation it's going to
help us going forward in the course so
the problem is this I have some
particular basis specified in this case
looks like the base is 1 1 and minus 2 1
then I have some vector for example the
vector 4 1 and what I want to know how
to do is how do I write that vector in
the B basis that is if I take my 4 1
what are the coefficients the C 1 and
the C 2 so that it can be written here
as a linear combination of the b one of
the B 2 now whatever you see a linear
combination I want to have a little bit
alarm bell go off in your mind because
linear combinations and multiply by a
matrix are the same thing indeed running
this linear combination is just the same
thing as saying that this is the
multiplication of the C 1 and C 2 by
these particular matrix the 1 1 minus 2
1 well what do I have I have a linear
system matrix times a vector is equal to
some other vector and I want to solve
that system and I could use some row
reductions I could use my normal trick
to solve a linear system of equations
but I want to talk about it in terms of
invertible matrices so the matrix that I
have here I can give it a name this
matrix is called P sub B this is a
matrix associated to every single basis
and you just take the vectors of the
basis and put them in as the columns of
the matrix and then the other thing to
note is that the C 1 C 2 we previously
define that to be the vector X written
in the B basis so this is just going to
be my vector X written in the B basis at
4 1 is my X and the C 1 C 2 is my X
written in the B basis now what I'm
talking about all of our two or all of
our three but the P matrix I'd get this
is going to be a square matrix we're
talking about different bases of our two
so they're all going to have two
components and there's going to be two
of them and in fact because the basis
where the vectors are linearly
independent if your row reduced is gonna
have a lead
one in every single column and so that
this matrix is going to be invertible so
I can go and reverse this process I've
got right now X is equal to a matrix
times the vector expert in the B basis I
can invert it and what I'm gonna get is
this I'm gonna get that the C 1 C 2 is
the inverse of that matrix times the 4 1
times the X and I know how to take the
inverse of a 2x2 matrix I swap the a and
the D put a minus sign in front of the B
and the C you divide out by ad minus BC
so I inverted this particular matrix and
now I can just multiply it out and what
do I get I get the value 2 minus 1
in fact we always have these two
different ways of solve systems you can
do the row reduction methodology or if
it's a square matrix you can just invert
it but the nice part about being will
invert it is now you can do it for every
single vector at once you just always
have to just do this multiplication you
don't have to repeat that row reduction
step every single time so if you can use
invertible matrices I usually suggest
that's the superior way to do it in
generality regardless I have now figured
it out my C 1 C 2 is equal to the 2
minus 1 and in doing so I actually can
come up with two sort of general
formulas the first is going to be that X
can always be written as this P matrix
times X written in the B basis or to
flip it around the other way X written
in the B basis can be the inverse of
this P matrix multiplied by n where the
where the PB matrix just has the first
and second basis vector as the first and
second call